Margaret Cruikshank papers, 1971-1986 LSC.1847
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Publications, 1977-1986; Series 1.; Boxes 1-10
  - New Lesbian Writing, 1982-1984; Subseries 3.; Boxes 9-10, 14
    - Gay Community News, 1984, Sept.; 2 issues (Box 14)
      See Box 10 for other book reviews and publicity materials for New Lesbian Writing.
  - Cruikshank publications, 1977-1986; Subseries 4.; Box 8, 14
    Chronological by date of publication.
    Published and unpublished papers and book reviews authored by Cruikshank (including those publications authored by Cruikshank under pseudonym); conference proposals and papers; rejection letters; clippings; newsletters; periodicals and related correspondence.
    - Publications authored by Cruikshank, 1979-1986; 7 folders (Box 8, Folder 2 - 8)
      Published and unpublished papers and book reviews authored by Cruikshank (including those publications authored by Cruikshank under pseudonym).
      Of note is the "We Were Fired: Lesbian Experiences with Academe" folder which includes an article by Cruikshank on why she got fired from her teaching job at the University of San Francisco (USF) in December, 1980 and the file of clippings, book reviews and correspondence relating to the publication of Lesbian Nuns: Breaking Silence edited by Rosemary Curb and Nancy Manahan.
    - Rejection letters, requests for review articles and correspondence, 1977-1979; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Lesbian Insider/Insighter/Inciter (Minneapolis, MN), 1981-1983; No. 5(November 1981) - No. 7(April 1982); No. 9(December 1982) - No. 10(March 1983); No. 12(February/March 1984) (Box 14)
      Consists of book reviews written by Cruikshank.
    - Philadelphia Gay News, 1985, March; Vol. no. 19(March 21, 1985) (Box 14)
      Book review authored by Cruikshank relating to the publication of Lesbian Nuns: Breaking Silence edited by Rosemary Curb and Nancy Manahan.
- Research files and notes, 1971-1986, n.d.; Series 2.; Box 11
  Includes publicity materials relating to various lesbian, gay and women's publications, books/bookstores and organizations, reviews of gay and lesbian literature, media coverage of lesbian and other women's issues, bibliographies, notes and conference/book review proposals by Cruikshank, calls for papers, articles about Cruikshank not related to her publications and related correspondence.
  - Correspondence and publicity relating to Lesbian-Feminist Study Clearinghouse, 1980-1981; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Publicity materials, 1971-1986, n.d.; 8 folders (Box 11, Folder 18 - 24)
    Relates mainly to lesbian, gay and women's publications, books/bookstores and organizations. Includes flyers, pamphlets and brochures; newspaper and magazine clippings; newsletters, bibliographies and related correspondence. There is some media coverage of the lesbian and gay political movement and lesbian and other women's issues, including articles and newsletter blurbs about Cruikshank that are not related to her books. Notes and proposals by Cruikshank for panels at the National Women's Studies Association (NWSA), Modern Language Association (MLA) and Gay Academic Union (GAU) annual conferences; proposed submissions for articles and book reviews by Cruikshank and calls for papers and requests to write and review are also included here.
    Folder 5 includes first edition of "In the Life" Newsletter of the West Coast Lesbian Collections in Oakland, CA (now the Mazer Lesbian Archives in West Hollywood, CA). Folder 7 includes March 1984 Gay Studies Newsletter (GSN) which covers Cruikshank's settlement with University of San Francisco (USF) where she was fired from her teaching job five months after she was hired.
  - Gay Community News, 1984, June-July; 3 issues - vol.11 no. 47(June 16, 1984); no. 50(July 7, 19840; vol.12 no. 10(September 22, 1984) (Box 14)
- Course syllabi and readings, 1982-1985; Series 3.; Box 11
  Course syllabi, bibliographies, course readings and student papers from Introduction to Women's Studies and Lesbian Gay Literature courses taught by Cruikshank at the City College of San Francisco.
  - Introduction to Women's Studies course syllabi, readings and bibliographies, 1983-1986; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Course syllabi and readings and related bibliographies from Introduction to Women's Studies course taught by Cruikshank at the City College of San Francisco; includes related bibliographies and workshop descriptions. Course readings include autobiographical writings, fiction, essays and criticism, including reprints of works by Alice Walker, Rosemary Curb and Adrienne Rich.
  - Lesbian Gay Literature course syllabi and readings, 1982-1986; 4 folders (Box 11, Folder 1 - 4)
    Course syllabi, readings, bibliographies, notes by Cruikshank, and student papers from Lesbian Gay Literature course taught by Cruikshank at the City College of San Francisco. Course readings include poems, lesbian autobiographical writings, fiction and literary criticism, including works by Sappho, Radclyffe Hall, May Sarton, Gertrude Stein, Jane Rule and Audre Lorde.
- Publications not authored by Cruikshank, 1979-1983, n.d.; Series 4.; Box 11, 14
  Published and published papers, reviews, manuscript drafts, galley proofs and bibliographies that were not written by Cruikshank.
  - Galley proof of Lesbian Crossroads by Ruth Baetz, 1980-1984; 3 folders (Box 11, Folder 6 - 8)
  - Manuscript draft of We Too Are Drifting by Gale Wilhelm, 1980-1984; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Not in THE NEW YORK TIMES Bibliographies, 1981; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Bibliographies compiled by Pat Case for The Not in THE NEW YORK TIMES Bibliography Series from the Alternative Press Collection housed in Special Collections at the University of Connecticut Library in Storrs. The bibliographies cover a variety of subjects including black women and feminism, anarchism and feminism, lesbianism and feminism, sexual harassment, economics, violence against women and pornography.
  - Published and unpublished papers, 1979-1983, n.d.; 6 folders (Box 11, Folder 11 - 16)
    Contains photocopies, typescripts and drafts of published and unpublished papers and theses that were not written by Cruikshank, including works by Susan Leigh Star, Martha Vicinus, Bonnie Zimmerman and various graduate students at The Institute for Advanced Study of Sexuality (San Francisco, CA) and U.C. Berkeley.
- Personal correspondence, 1971-1976; Series 5.; Boxes 12-13
  Personal correspondence from Sue Ebbers to Cruikshank and several photos.
  Chronological by date of correspondence.
  - Correspondence, 1971-1972; 13 folders (Box 12, Folder 1 - 13)
    Correspondence from Sue Ebbers to Cruikshank.
    See Box 13 for later correspondence dated 1973-1976.
  - Correspondence, 1973-1976; 15 folders (Box 13, Folder 1 - 13)
    See Box 12 for earlier correspondence dated 1971-1972. Folder 13 consists of correspondence from Cruikshank to Ebbers.
  - Photographs, 1972; 2 folders (Box 13, Folder 14 - 15)
    Two photographs of Sue Ebbers and four headshots of Cruikshank.